

# Chase M. Marcum

Software Engineer/Web Developer

4008 SE Kibling Ct., Troutdale, OR 97060 Email: <a href="mailto:chase.m.marcum@gmail.com">chase.m.marcum@gmail.com</a> Website: <a href="mailto:chasemarcum.net">chase.m.marcum@gmail.com</a>

Phone: (503) 888-5604

2011 - present

2010 - 2012

# **Summary of Qualifications**

Extensive education on <b>software development</b> through <b>practical application</b> and <b>theory</b> ,
encompassing design, development, deployment, and maintenance of a software product
Proven ability to make informed decisions, adapt to situations, and seek understanding.

☐ Ability to **manage** and **prioritize** multiple tasks/projects and deadlines simultaneously.

□ Over 14 years of successful experience in **management**, **supervision** and **customer service**.

# **Technical Skills**

**ASP.NET MVC** WCF HTML5 & CSS Java ASP.NET LINQ JavaScript **JUnit** Windows **C# Programing** C++ Programing **jQuery Visual Studio SQL Server Bootstrap** Win 8 App Dev NUnit Knockout **Source Control** ISON

MS Office Suite Excel PowerPoint Word

## **Education**

# **Oregon Institute of Technology**

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering Technology Expected completion: June 2015

GPA: 3.64

# Mt. Hood Community College

Associate of Applied Science in Computer Science Honors: Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society, President's Honor

GPA: 3.96

# **Skills and Experience**

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Team Lead in Oregon Tech's junior software development project, utilizing the Agile and SCRUM software
development process to gather requirements, model, analyze, develop and integrate an n-tiered
architecture product.

☐ The ability to identify, formulate, and solve software engineering problems, through the specification, design, implementation, and testing of software systems.

Wilsonville, OR

Gresham, OR

□ Knowledge of data structures, theory of computation, operating systems, compilers, programming languages, and computer architecture.

☐ Understanding of the **software development life cycles (SDLC)** of design, development, deployment, and maintenance.

#### **IT SERVICES**

П	Ensured:	all company	, facilities/de	partments are up,	running and	onerational	365 da	vs a vear
_	Liisuicu		, racilities, ac	partificitis are up,	Turning and	operacionai	303 uu	ys a year.

- ☐ Primary IT **support** for seven medical clinic locations, business office, and billing department.
- □ Planned, organized, scheduled, and coordinated diverse IT projects and activities.
- ☐ Preserved the **integrity** of the company's website by **routine updates** and **revisions**.
- ☐ Sustained and managed all company's social media accounts.

## MANAGEMENT, SALES, AND CUSTOMER SERVICE

- ☐ Ensured overall excellence in operations, risk management, training, and compliance performance.
- ☐ Scheduled staff and store resources to ensure **appropriate coverage** to **meet company goals**.
- ☐ Continuously **improved** company's **performance**, **operational excellence** and associate proficiency.
- ☐ **Provided positive** and **constructive feedback** to help employees improve their skills.
- ☐ Led and trained customer service standards and achieved top sales results.
- ☐ **Identified opportunities** and referred to appropriate divisions within company.
- **Developed** new business with current and prospective customers.
- ☐ Assisted in growing extensive sales, operations and product knowledge through ongoing **training**.
- ☐ Formulated business strategies and drove results by aligning store goals with company goals.

# **Employment History**

### 2012 – 2013 IT/Facilities Specialist

Northwest Urgent Care, LLC Gresham, OR

I was brought on to Northwest Urgent Care to solely take over the **Networking** and **IT** responsibilities of the business that was previously managed by a third party company. I started with Northwest Urgent Care to **gain working knowledge** and **experience** in the computer industry while attending school at Oregon Tech full-time. I was able to utilize many of my previous work experience skills to this position that allowed me to excel in my duties and responsibilities. With my customer **service skills** I was able to establish and maintain **effective working relationships** with co-workers and vendors. Through my **management skills** I was able to **plan**, **organize**, **schedule**, and **coordinate** diverse IT and/or building maintenance **projects** and activities. This position also allowed me to expand and gain on my current knowledge of Networking and computer that I have gained through school and experience. Key accomplishments that I have done at Northwest Urgent Care are as follows:

- ☐ In August 2012 I effectively **planned** and **implemented** an upgrade of the clinics Electronic Medical Records system from Centricity CPS 8 to Centricity CPS 10. This included installing a new **server** to become the new **primary domain controller**, repurposing the existing servers and setting one up as a new **terminal server**, transferring the **SQL** database to the new **SQL server**, and upgrading a majority of the clinics workstations.
- □ I was part of the project management team that **designed**, **planned**, and **executed** the building of the Urgent Care Express Clinic that opened in November 2012. This included installing a new terminal **server** to the domain, setting up new **workstations**, setting up a public wireless network, and creating a large digital sign for the front windows.
- Designed, built, and managed the website <a href="http://www.u-c-express.com">http://www.u-c-express.com</a> for our Urgent Care Express Clinic, including the mobile website.
- ☐ **Preserved** and **sustained** the **integrity** of the company's websites and all company's social media accounts.
- □ Participated in the process of **planning** and **implementing** a rebranding of all clinics to reflect name change to Northwest Urgent Care. This included obtaining bids and communicating to different vendors to change existing building signage, replace marketing material, and redesign the website and social media accounts.

## 2006 – 2010 Assistant Banking Center Manager

**Bank of America** 

Portland, OR

I was recruited to Bank of America to become the Assistant Banking Center Manager for the highest volume banking center within the Portland Metro Market, Eastport Plaza Banking Center. I came to Bank of America to learn, grow and experience the **operations** of banking, while also **improving** and **utilizing** my previous **management skills** and **experience**. Through the partnership of my Market Executive Manager, we determined the next natural step for my development was to step into the Personal Banker role to further my skills in sales, while also assisting other banking centers in **operations**. In the transition period with Bank of America I have had great experience in assisting other banking centers, while also **building relationships** and **networking** with other associates of our market. My additional accomplishments within the company were as follows:

- □ Within my first four months with Bank of America I was able to bring the banking center from a previous operational audit score of 6 out of 10 to an **improved** score of 8. Through **managing** and **coaching** I was also able to **improve** tellers **achieving** their referral **goals** from 43% to 100% of tellers meeting or **exceeding** their referral **goals**.
- □ For the first quarter of 2007, Eastport Plaza Banking Center was at 87% of their goal for checking account production. Upon completing the fourth quarter of 2007 the banking center was at 109% to goal with an increase in performance in all other sales areas by 20%. This placed Eastport Plaza for performance to goals within the top 3 banking centers in the Portland Metro Market.

## 2005 – 2006 Small Business Specialist

**US Bank** 

Beaverton, OR

Within my first year with US Bank I initially stepped into a Personal Banker role with the intention to learn banking sales and operations. As a Personal Banker I performed as a top new banker within the region. I was quickly identified as a management candidate and was introduced into the "Emerging Leaders" program due to my past management experience, sales experience and my performance as a personal banker. US Bank then created a pilot Small Business Specialist position and it was my next natural step for positive growth within the company. As a Small Business Specialist, I went through extensive training and job shadowing. The Small Business Specialist position gave me a great opportunity to build small business sales. US Bank is now expanding the role within the company. My additional accomplishments within the company were as follows:

- □ In 2006 through personal bookings and referrals to my Business Banking Officer I **produced 1.4 million dollars** in new small business loans for third guarter and **1.2 million dollars** in fourth guarter.
- □ Beaverton Main Branch was recognized in the region as one of the **top branches** for their small business **growth** in 2006, ranked 3 out of 77.

## 1997 – 2005 **Operations/Merchandise Manager**

**Old Navy** 

Clackamas, OR

My **experience** revolved around **multiple** store locations and various **management** titles. Responsibilities within my role as a manager **continually grew** in size and scope. They **encompassed** expanding dollar volumes, **complex training**, and **development** of various levels of staff. In **addition** to my regular duties I had taken on district positions that include District "StaffWorks" Program Expert, District Operational Audit team member, and assisted as a store opener in various locations throughout the region.